

MARIYANA ARABOVA

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Overview

I am a Front End Developer with over 2 years of experience planning, coding, testing and maintaining websites, working on small to large scale projects. My general skills are in HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript, with keen focus on good programming practices and standards. Build modern responsive interfaces from scratch or Photoshop designs. All conforming to internet standards and fully browser compatible. Writing clear and semantic code, which favors in SEO.

I am passionate about new trends in technology, which allow me widen professional abilities and scope. Analytical mindset, being creative in problem solving and quick learning. Team player who works well with others at various levels. Looking for a position in a creative and challenging environment, where I could continue learning and improving my skill set.

<u>Technical skills and competences</u>

- Languages: HTML 5, CSS 2(CSS 3), Javascript, SQL, Clips, UML, XML, C++(basic knowledge), PHP 5 (basic knowledge);
- Frameworks and Libraries: Jquery(UI & Mobile), Twitter Bootstrap(newcomer), PhoneGap, Kendo UI;
- Graphics Software: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, CorelDraw
- Other:
 - Experience with responsive design and cross platform mobile apps
 - Experience with with version control systems SVN
 - Computer networks(TCP/P, POP3, SMTP, HTTP protocols) basic knowledge
 - o SEO

Professional Experience

Front End Developer at Proxiad Bulgaria, Sofia, Bulgaria

January 2014 – Present

- **Duties** Front end development of hybrid mobile applications (iOS and Anroid), convert flash animation to html5 animation, development of newsletters.
- Technologies: HTML 5, CSS 3, Javascript
- Projects Proxiad App, Vibia App, Moselle Tourisme, etc



Front End Developer at Iteco Ltd., Sofia, Bulgaria

August 2012 – December 2013

- Duties Front-end development (HTML/CSS/Javascript) tasks, client side development, crossbrowser related problems solving, mobile web development and performing different tasks in the field of web design.
- **Technologies:** HTML (5), CSS (3), Jquery(UI & Mobile), PhoneGap, Kendo UI,PHP (Zend and CodeIgniter);
- Projects Bonusinside, Cash4feedback, Iteco

SEO agent at Zetbase Ltd, Nicosia (Cyprus)

October 2011 – February 2012

- Duties SEO optimization of sites in google.fr
- **Projects** http://seo-referencement.com, http://seo-referencem

Receptionist at Four Brothers Plus One (Royal Crest Motor Inn motel), Hampton beach (USA)

May 2010/2011 - September 2010/2011

• **Duties –** Making reservations over the phone, signing people in the motel, basic troubleshooting.,

Education and Qualifications

BSc Information Systems

2008-2013, Sofia University "St. Kliment Ohridski", Department of Mathematics and Informatics

High School: Profile foreign languages - French

2003-2008, 33 Language School "Saint Sofia", Sofia, Bulgaria

Languages

English (Intermediate)

French (Intermediate)

Bulgarian (Native)

References are available on request.